

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · FULL-STACK

Santa Clara, CA 95051

Professional Summary _

Frameworks, Systems, and Concepts

Skilled engineer with a passion for developing clean, maintainable, and efficient code. Primarily experienced with Java and Ruby but adapts quickly when exposed to new languages and frameworks. Leverages strong technical, analytical, and troubleshooting skills while working well both independently and with a team.

Technical Skills_

Proficient Languages Java, Ruby, Python, SQL

Competent Languages C, C++, C#, JavaScript, HTML / CSS, PHP, Perl and shell scripting

Alexa Skills, Ruby on Rails, Apache Hadoop / Hive, jQuery, OpenAPI, Version Control Systems, Continuous Integration, Build Automation, Test-Driven Development, Service-oriented Architecture, SOAP and

RESTful Services, Object Oriented and Functional Programming,

Common Design Patterns, Agile Methodologies

Experience

Amazon.com, Inc

SOFTWARE ENGINEER ON ALEXA SHOPPING PRODUCT ADVISER

East Palo Alto, CA May 2018 - Present

- · Created a pipeline to ingest unanswered Alexa product questions to then post to the product Q&A section to enrich Alexa's knowledge base.
- · Helped develop a service to assist customers in setting up new smart home devices and connect them to Alexa, as well as send notifications upon product delivery giving instructions on how to ask Alexa for setup assistance.
- · Worked on the creation of an Alexa Skill to voice-enable seasonal and evergreen gifting experiences, surfacing ideas and product recommendations from the Amazon gift finder and other sources.
- Contributed to numerous other Alexa Shopping projects including superlative product search, voice-enabled grocery checkout, and product review questions.

Tripadvisor

Boston, MA / Palo Alto, CA

May 2013 - Jul. 2017

- SOFTWARE ENGINEER ON COMMERCE Contributed extensively to nearly every major Commerce system including processing of inventory and bidding feeds from external providers (e.g. Expedia, Priceline), backend services handling core Auction Logic, frontend offer display, outbound deeplink generation, click tracking, billing, fraud detection, system health monitoring, and generation of var-
- ious reports and auction bidding recommendations for providers to use as a guide in their bidding • Frequently pushed for and undertook projects aimed at reducing technical debt, removing outdated features and unnecessary cruft, increasing test coverage and system monitoring, and otherwise improving the stability of our systems and maintainability of the codebase
- · Initiated and managed a significant rewrite and refactoring of the team's pre-existing Hadoop / Hive based reporting system resulting in runtime performance improvements of up to 60% and ultimately led to various important internal and externally accessible reports and datasets being available significantly earlier in the day
- Worked on the Hotel Availability Service calling out to external APIs to obtain real-time availability and pricing information

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute

Troy, NY

HELP DESK CONSULTANT

Jan. 2012 - May 2013 Assisted students and faculty with various software and hardware issues

• Regularly performed or assisted with various diagnostic, repair, and configuration procedures including virus removal, computer security, printer and driver configuration, networking, OS installation and configuration, E-mail, and more

Adobe Systems Inc

Seattle, WA

Jun. 2011 - Aug. 2011

RELEASE ENGINEERING INTERN

• Wrote scripts for the purpose of heuristic analysis of automated builds

Authored tools and automation to assist with various repetitive tasks and procedures

Education

Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute

Trov, NY

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

CONCENTRATION IN GAMES & SIMULATION ARTS & SCIENCES

Aug. 2009 - May 2013